so as a conference organiz one hopes
everything goes smoothly or at least we
we like to present the impression that
everything is going smoothly uh but
there's a lot of things happen behind
the scenes and unfortunately one of
those things that happens sometimes is
our speakers drop out at the last minute
which happened last Wednesday one of our
speakers unfortunately couldn't make it
uh because they had left the company
they were
representing um so I had to ask um some
people to act as backups and uh these
were people also very highly rated by
our uh cfp process uh obviously we only
have a certain amount of slots but I'm
very pleased to say um that Gregor and
Alexandra from no Unity have stepped
into the breach we'll be presenting
today uh and they've literally been
pulling their slides together over the
weekend um I would tell you more about
them both um but they we didn't even get
a chance for them to send me a bio so I
I could make something up
would you like to me to make up a bio
for you no no probably very sensible um
so uh we're going to kick off in a
second just check the zoom is working it
is it seems to be back um and they're
going to be talking about building a
genz Search application for 30 million
students with llms and search so please
Round of Applause for Gregor
cool I hope you can hear me all Yes
sounds good cool uh yeah Welcome to our
talk about search and LMS uh building a
gen genz search up for more than 13
million students um today we're going to
talk a bit about uh how we in a Unity
build our search this is our quick
agenda um we're going to first quickly
introduce ourselves tell you a bit about
who we are and what we do then we're
going to focus on quickly about uh
introducing you how our search works
getting both context you to understand
the rest uh of the talk afterwards then
we're going to talk through our journey
so far of LMS and then have of sprinkle
in what we for and then conclude with
overall learnings that we had and
hopefully some takeaways for you as
well cool then let's jump in um so yeah
I'm one of the co-founders of no unity
and we basically uh yeah co-funded the
unity around four years ago with three
other friends uh from 2020 uh and back
then we were still in school actually
and realized that education is actually
stuck in the 80s um so education is a
super analog so things just happen on
paper there are books passing around
nothing is digital yet B education is
super related so basically students
learn on their own there actually is not
really much uh group learning happening
especially um they have they learn
sometimes in person together but not
really together and it's also generally
speaking not really social online but on
the flip side
students actually spend a lot of time on
their phones on Tik Tok and Instagram
and kind of yeah waste their time a bit
there and don't really spend it anything
meaningful and lastly actually education
is still quite privileged so especially
still like even here in Germany
basically the household income
correlates quite quite high with your
educational degree in yend um and we're
quite well the country but in especially
all other countries developing countries
it's even worse um so there you need to
spend some money to actually get good
education so we kind of realized all of
that and basically yeah jumped
interaction to actually build a product
for students so build an app uh for for
students that kind of brings education
through the 21st century our goal was
always to build the daily learning
companion so to build an app basically
accompanies students throughout their
whole Liv basically from fifth grade
onwards to uh currently up to your your
12 13 grades your a levels in the future
all then towards University level and
our goal was basically to build
something from students for students um
so there a lot of Education products out
there aexs out there but they all always
built by teachers built by older people
basically where it's always a more top
down scenario so our approach was rather
to actually build a social app where
students can can basically yeah it's
built by students for for students in
that sense and we basically built this
companion which is highly personalized
and the second important thing that we
focus on is it actually content is all
by students so the content on the
platform is all created so all user
generated content that students
basically
created and then actually upload it to
the platform so the good students
basically the ones in Germany calleda
sometimes uh they are basically ones
uploading content and basically putting
on the platform we have around 1.5
million content pieces of on the
platform and then basically those good
students actually get likes get feedback
and interaction from other students
there and last we actually focus on is
the social part to building up a
community where actually students can
help each other can learn together uh
through group chat content through
interactions basic can learn together in
a more joyful and fun way so we launched
that in around September of 2020 um and
actually yeah we kind of Blown Away by
the success it had so actually now uh
users LED it basically uh so we got a
lot of massive amount of positive
reviews actually uh were climbed the top
three of all app store charts in front
of Tik Tok other apps um and yeah really
kind of made a big big dent on the on
the user side and there's also a lot of
yeah content about us being created plus
I guess the the also social side we
actually did see that we have quite some
impact on students so I think everybody
in the company actually had once a story
where they met somebody in the train or
on on the street when we're like a
hoodie of the company and basically then
the person actually talks to them say
say hey actually your app kind of Saved
My a levels without you I would have I
wouldn't have gotten my a levels
basically and something also much of
Ates us quite quite heavily and that
also actually resulted in quite quite
good user growth we're actually now at
more than 13 million users in the
platform um we also expanded to more
than eight more than 11 countries by now
um basically almost a big all big
European countries also now in US active
in Colombia and in Turkey basically as
you can see also still growing uh so
still still continue to grow we only
launched turkey around two weeks ago and
basically also still growing on user
side and also now a team of around 60
people uh here in Berlin also raised uh
funding basically so raised in total
more than 25 million of funding and now
kind of yeah grown to to a more stable
company um quickly about us as a last so
I said I'm Greer I'm one of the
co-founders um I basically yeah kind of
built the first app and the first search
version so basically I'm more technical
background uh back then 2020 actually
started to build the whole thing and
also built our first search um nowadays
um more a product sites with leading our
product team um but still yeah quite
deeply involved into
search Hello um yeah so I'm Alexandra I
joined Unity no Unity one year ago to be
part of uh search and basically before
that I worked also in at tag but on the
medical side was helping medical
students to learn better but basically
yeah now it's me Gregor uh
within all the effort on search
together cool then let's talk quickly
about search at Unity um I brought you
some quick numbers to go over them um so
basically quick context from the product
perspective um one called use case that
students have of us is actually finding
study notes um for their exams for the
homework they have so those study notes
I said we have around 1.5 million of
those study notes and then basically
students search in in the app for those
study notes so either via actual
classical search but also VI
recommendations they can actually get
those those study notes and around 70%
of our users of our sessions actually
have a search inem so quite a search
Focus product General on a quick number
side I said we have around 40 million
documents indexes includes the content I
mentioned but also includes flash cards
folders the users themselves it's uh
hosted all on elastic search we search
in since GetGo basically then we have
around 500,000 searches per day um on a
good day um it's quite fluctuating
because students basically are less
active on the weekend which they also
deserve but they also didn't take a
break there so it's uh typically quite
yeah 500k you typically have like a good
good
weekday besides that you also have eight
languages which makes everything a bit
more complicated because actually to
always support eight different languages
in your work then we're pretty small
search team so we have one search
engineer Alexandra we have half a PM on
there we have like 10% of me roughly um
and 10% of a back engineer that's all
the search team currently con working
there and we but so far I actually ran
around 200 AB tests in our total life
just on search um so gener speaking
quite an AB test focused company quite
data driven and also especially in
search we also aest quite quite heavily
and so I've gotten to to
there um yes so I wanted to show you
basically what we're dealing with and
yesterday I think we were discussing how
hard it is to work with the PDFs and
PDFs also can be different and as you
can see our PDFs
are yeah pretty pretty complicated to
extract the information you can have a
graphs you can have flots you can have
diagrams mind maps and sometimes just
like super weird pictures with bad
writing so yeah that just leads to a lot
of complications in terms of like what
informations we're using uh in Search
and how we
process so I just wanted to quickly show
you basically our back end
infrastructures
so when student is uploading their
content after it goes through the review
and being approved of course we put it
uh through the OCR to extract the
transcripts from all the
pages um then we have some machine
learning models on outl that basically
get some additional information about
the documents such as is this document
is primarily visual or is it readable
how structured it is um then we get of
course the text embeddings uh we got it
from openi and we store it in
DB as a cash um all our events are
coming from our front end and being
streamed in big quy
um then we have uh a little small
service in hugging phase because it's
easy and simple to host it there uh that
basically predicts the likelihood of a
user to convert which helps us to
identify to which users we can show
advertisement and which not in our
search results and then we have the
whole basically goes to our syncing
service that gets data from post Crest
uh and puts it into elastic search um
yeah that's that's pretty much it for
our
backand and in the end it goes to our
mobile app which we from the search side
there is mostly the notes but of course
we have a flash cards
quizzes uh chats so we also responsible
for all of that also there is the Feit
component but that's that's a little bit
abandoned now
cool switching over to our journey so
far with large language models in search
so as a as a quick Contex basically we
actually pretty early on so actually
when when Chad gbt wasn't even out so
gbt three times we already looked into
into LMS um because actually for us
there's a quite quite uh high potential
because in the end uh as you can see we
have quite a lot of unstructured content
and LM is actually really good at
handling unstructured content so
actually pretty early on jumped on the
train of actually trying to use um
trying to use large language models so
actually the first swing that we did
sorry the first thing we did actually
was to extract keywords so as you can
see the documents here as also mentioned
are handwritten and they're we OCR them
but it's pretty tricky to actually get a
good transcript out of them and they're
therefore actually quite noisy um and
have quite a lot of unnecessary stuff in
them being it errors that they o are
makes but also unimportant stuff by the
student so our goal was actually to
reduce the content down to the important
signals so basically use GPT extract
keywords out of that document and then
basically use a those keywords in the
search to basically have search over
those keywords and B also actually show
those keywords as you can see here
actually show them to the user so kind
of as a proof point for the user hey
this content piece actually matches what
I have search
for the uh why we actually did the
search part is because priv we we
actually heavily searched on title and
description and now the goal was
actually to increase the recall by also
for tail terms the terms were that
actually a bit more rarely happening
that don't appear in any titles or
descriptions we can still find relevant
um content for
them and how we did that actually as
already mentioned we tried it a couple
of times actually pre GPT so before GPT
existed we tried it based on the size
for example of the text we said hey okay
if the text size is bigger is likely an
important word we tried that but worked
at lash uh we also tried it uh with some
with some other ristics based on TF
ideas and so on but it's all quite
tricky and then actually gbt was kind of
the first real solution for that because
it actually just enabled us to just give
the text WR the good prompt for it and
get keywords out of it the only main
issue was that we did that around when
gbt 3 came out which basically meant it
was quite a expensive because there was
still quite a price tag back then to it
and it also was not that great from a
quality standpoint um so actually we
only were able to run on a couple of
thousand condent pieces because
otherwise it would have been too
expensive um but in the end we actually
ran this as test on a couple of content
pieces we actually saw that showing
those keywords actually had a
significant impact on the search
performance um and basically yeah for
the search is basic where where they
were shown but unfortunately the
keywords as as a way Toc recall didn't
work um quick word on how we test search
basically as mentioned we AB test almost
everything or everything we do on the
search side it's a bit tricky to
evaluate it because in the end there's
no purchase event people can just study
the content but they can't purchase it
so it's a bit more tricky to kind of
Define what the goal of a search is and
what we did uh quite early on is
actually kind of look into Data quite a
lot and figure out what actually is a
meaningful event a user can do in search
thenan correlates well with a desired
action of ours and it's desired action
being actually them retaining um on on
longterm basis and what we saw actually
is that for us what's important is a
person actually really studying this
content and we defined it basically as
spending at least 120 seconds in its
content piece which means you actually
had a meaningful interaction we studied
it and actually this for us a positive
indication that the search worked so all
the IB tests that we run we actually
valuate on uh search fill rate basically
search to study event and study event is
set are the 12 seconds um
consumption plus we also take a look at
St like retention to actually also see
if there's a secondary impact on on the
day on day or we on weak retention for
users
um and yeah basically one kind of core
learning we actually got out of that is
that in the end gbt fre was bad not sure
if anybody played around with GPT back
then but compared to nowadays it was
expensive and it really didn't scale um
but luckily things have changed since
then and models got a lot
better um yeah the next iteration or
exploration was actually trying to
introduce kind of Google style questions
uh to our users so why we did it um well
students are kind of lazy they don't
like to type a lot and also to keep them
uh like within the interaction of the
content we wanted to try something new
um it was in a December last year so as
you can imagine models were still not so
good so we did a simple thing we took
the search term we got the search
results before then we sent basically
the search term uh and like the title
and descriptions to the GPT and
generated questions and some short
answers to it um
so as a learning um it was a great
opportunity to try something new because
as you can imagine like before like the
language models to do something like
that you would need to mostly humans to
generate something like this and we
realized okay we actually need to try
something new on UI maybe the content
might be not the best but at least we
will try to understand how will users
interact with that and that was great
opportunity uh which we tried uh as I
said unfortunately the quality wasn't
the best because it was gpg 3.5 it was
slow uh that's also what you users don't
like but in the end the learning was
like okay we can try things out easily
and like see if it scks or not in terms
of like designs and like Fast
iterations actually spent like probably
like a day or two on that feature so it
was actually pretty pretty fast the
second thing we tried is then to
actually look into using uh an companion
like an AI chat basically in the search
um it was similar hypotheses to before
basically students are again lazy and
students also struggle to actually
formulate good Search terms so they
basically they often typ kind of
anything they think about which could be
too broad or could be kind of weird
gibberish um there and thus they
actually find or get nonrelevant results
which then basically leads them to a bad
search rate so what our goal was here B
to help them formulate a good search
term and help them kind of find good
results what we did then basically is we
showed uh a i entry point at the bottom
of the search page and we also we
actually looked into moments where user
might be lost so for example user spends
10 seconds on the page without doing
anything or user kind of Scrolls to for
10 results without clicking on anything
and then basically said okay in those
moments we actually kind of nudge them
to go into this into this chat so kind
chat pop up a bit kind of like hint them
to go into it and basically once they're
in it we actually showed you options to
either summarize direct this topics get
the concrete answer or actually to kind
of tell us hey I want better content
it's a pretty simple way to is telling
us okay the results are bad and then we
actually then let them into a flow to
rewrite their questions we actually
afterwards ask them hey uh what do you
action need or can describe the homework
you currently have that kind of try to
actually yeah that for them they
actually give us a better better search
term um unfortunately it didn't work uh
why does why didn't not work because
students didn't see that thing uh so
even though we try to n it students are
quite quite focused and don't have a
high attention span so basically didn't
even recognize something was happening
down on the screen so nobody actually
clicked into it so the funnel didn't
really didn't really work so our goal
was okay it's the same thing again but a
bit more
visibility so we then basically tried is
a V2 out of it um and this time actually
what we did is do it the quite
aggressive way of actually putting the
AI answer directly as a the default
answer in in the search so quite a bold
move there um and also already had
basically some follow-up questions down
below you can basically ask um all kind
of get clarification on down there um
and we also added a AI generated summary
at the top um plus which still show
content for users below so it's kind of
our approach to kind of Now flip it
around and make it as aggressive as
possible to see if students actually
like it interesting thing now it
actually was sign significantly negative
on our metric because a um latency is an
issue so just it just takes quite a lot
longer to actually generate this answer
than it takes to just show results um
and B where we also learned a bit kind
I've learned the first glimpse of is
that students in our case they actually
just one content so they actually have a
pretty clear need to actually get a
study note and they don't really want to
have a summarized answer they actually
want to have a full study note so they
kind of were not really interested in
that uh text down there which we
actually we tested that so what we did
we actually in the final UI we actually
had like a c more button so we can
actually could see how many people click
on that see more button so how many
people are actually reading the text and
we saw that basically nobody did that so
nobody actually read the text everybody
just went through the content um
straight away plus the issue that we
also have is that the quality of text is
quite varying because in the end
sometimes GPT has really good answers
sometimes really bad answers and it's
actually hard to really control that in
the
end um the next thing that we tried was
not so much on the UI side but actually
on the backend side and the idea came
from
the project of learning to rank and at
some moment I realized that like I'm
looking at the errors of my model and I
saw that there is like significant
amount of information that it's
missing and yes on the one side we give
a transcripts a text and some user
interaction data but the model has no
idea about the quality of the thing like
how does it even look does it have
uh pictures how good are pictures is
there like a description for the picture
and the first thing we wanted to try
basically okay can we somehow understand
like the quality of the content without
any user interaction because of course
there is a lot of new content that are
coming in our hands and we rely a lot on
like in ranking on the user interaction
data but if there is no user interaction
data there should be other quality
um identifiers so one of them uh was
basically
readability like simple I open uh the
note can I even read it can I scan it is
it clear for me or not um I Al have to
say before that we try to uh human
labels but not regarding the readability
we kind of try to put everything in one
concept of like beautiful stud note
beautiful means it structure I like it I
want to interact with it and that didn't
work at all so that's why we decided
okay how we can understand the concept
of like beautiful and basically split it
in different things and the first thing
was
readability um so basically what I did I
took uh the bunch of the PDFs I threw it
in gb4 and let it label from like
readable non-readable perspective uh
then we took this data basically trained
the classification model and uh then
pass all our data through it
and the same we did for the concept of
struers which was a little bit more
complicated because if I even ask any of
you what does it mean structured content
um the same problem llm has because it's
even more stupid to understand what's
structured but from our definition
structured means it has a highd lines it
has some diagrams to help you to
understand the information it has some
highlights into basically anything it
helps you to comprehend the content and
here the work was a little bit more
complicated the prompting was a little
bit more complicated in classification
but in the end it all worked
out we also in the end trained just a
classification model based on the data
from the GP for the
structuredness and uh did the test and
we had very positive uh results
basically where we would boost the
readable and highly structured content
and de boost um the bad content and also
now we do like post filtering where we
see like okay if even like it happens in
our final results we see the know that
it's not very liked by students from
like user data and it's not readable we
still filter it out so that worked
pretty good so the learning is basically
LMS has LMS gives us possibility to do
like the basic machine learning tasks uh
very
easily cool the next thing we tried
which kind of in the same direction is
that we actually always had this issue
of bad ocrs as already mentioned and a
set content is basically handwritten and
it's pretty tricky for any good or for
any
yeah basically out of the box OCR model
to actually give you good results here
so we actually couldn't really use OCR
or the content that much um in the first
place we actually then now did as a kind
of follow up from the extract keybo
thing is actually to use gp4 or vision
and just give it the whole picture and
just basically let it actually create
the transcript or the OCR from gbt for
vision which actually works a lot better
than the classical OCR models because in
the end a can actually understands the
structure you actually kind of can put
down the tables and and mark down and
put can put on headlines and markdown
and actually gives you way better
quality um also when just looking at the
actual text especially for handwritten
stuff uh typical ocrs are pretty bad at
it we actually did that then for around
100,000 of our content pieces um and run
them for gbd4 vision the issue here
again is which again is a a similar
learning is that good llms are still not
cheap so if you really have the scale as
we have like 1.5 million documents
running all that through a GPT is still
quite expensive but as you also can can
see the price gets cheaper and cheaper
so already that is a lot cheaper than
what we did back then with gpt3 um so I
guess also in the future staff will get
cheaper even more but right now it's
still for us at least a bit tricky to do
stuff on really all content Pieces Just
because of the the price of it uh but
nevertheless it's for us a really good
tool really get better quality content
out of it which then now using for a
couple other features
I will go quickly through this one
basically we tried uh to do just the
basic autoc corrector did you mean just
with LMS and uh we something fast and
something
CH uh and we tried like small uh llama
model for that and the results
were um that the good LS are not fast
the small LS are fast but basically bad
and we did have actually good results
for languages as English and German but
we had pretty bad results for languages
such as
polish um yeah which I think um again
coming back to we're hoping that the
good models will be
cheaper uh another big project that we
did was not specifically search uh it it
was basically my summer with uh with my
partner in crime in AI Squad where we we
needed to build a knowledge
graph of the knowledge Concepts why
because in our application we want to
support students in continuous learning
for that we need to understand where
they stand in like on like certain
topics like they learn what they didn't
learn where we need to help to do that
we we need to understand from our
content
what the topic is content is focused on
and then basically recommend the next
topic or like repeat the current one or
related ones um that was one of the
reason another reason we want to help
users also
continuously um like learn things with
quizzes and basically the idea was to
generate the quizzes and the flashcards
based on these topics and of course as
you can all probably know you can use
this information
in search so how did this work actually
this was a third attempt right um the
first attempt was uh based on a school
curriculum that didn't work then second
attempt I don't know what was the second
attempt but basically like this is the
third attempt uh and the idea was to
build this for like all the countries
that were serving surfing
to um when we started we actually had a
baseline uh from the US schol system
where we had the knowledge
areas um and basically like the main
entities and the topics that students
will study from these knowledge areas so
the first task was actually to identify
this knowledge areas and build the model
for the for this knowledge area so
basically to classify the content into
specific subject So currently it's like
22 knowledge areas also interesting
point um the classification there is
different for different type of subjects
so we had much more complications with
like language type things like English
German then just like biology and math
because for
like for for language task you have a
literature things and then you have a
grammar things and then you have have
the analysis things and it's just much
more precise than uh
the normal science put it this way so
that was the first thing the second
thing was entities so where we get
entities from Search terms so basically
what I did I basically extracted the the
most popular Search terms uh the body
Search terms and the tail Search terms
from each country then the first uh
position was to extract the
meaningful sorry to extract meaningful
uh information from the Search
terms um which was done easily you can
get it but of course from the Search
terms we have also a lot of garbage a
lot of super generic things as like math
grade five which were not interesting
thing and then basically there was the
huge work being done on like leaning
D duplicating this ambiguation part so I
think
like that was one of the main learnings
that LMS are fast and they can generate
pretty smart things but I had a feeling
that I'm still working with like a
student who is pretending to be
professional but not very professional
just trying to produce a lot of stuff so
which led to the situation where we had
like six state is the duplication
process and which we had to run several
times uh over and over because as you
know in some case I'm just like misses
things and then you just basically
you're basically like seing information
through then we had some disambiguation
jobs disambiguation meaning I have some
very generic term like analysis of the
text and then I need to Define okay is
this super generic or not uh if it's not
super generic taking into account um the
description please rewrite it in
something more specific that can be used
and the final thing was translating all
of that into different
languages
and yeah basically the duplicating and
cleaning after that there was a huge
part done of like assignment of those
listings which wasn't done by Me was
done by my partner uh which was a huge
job and basically now we're working on
the linking entities to actually predict
like the next topic or uh the related
content yeah as I said uh LMS are great
but it's it's it Demands a lot a lot of
time to actually have something like
clean that can be used by the users and
by
us cool the the last thing we tried
actually only last week I think um is we
actually kind of did the the next
iteration of the AI and search thing
which was day time actually building a
whole AI results page Why did we do this
again um a was that we saw that in our
app we also have now have like a
separate AI conversation basically
students can chat with an AI tool and we
actually see that being used quite
heavily so around 25% of students
actually use it every every day
actually our goal was here kind to merge
together the AI chat conversation and
our search in a more conversational
conversational style search plus
actually remov the necessity for
students to open content because I
actually directly see the result on the
on the page T what we did actually this
time was also to think about what
actually constitutes a good content
piece um so our eyes it should actually
be for student really short and precise
but it should also be colorful have
illustrations and also actually has to
be trustworthy because uh a big part is
that students actually trust our
conscient because they're produced by
other students so they actually know
somebody get got an A for that or like a
one for that because they actually learn
of that content so we actually did this
time was to a add the illustrations so
actually we extracted from content so
our most popular content run against
some ml models over there to actually
stract the images out of that then use
that you search plus we also directly
linked the content this is based on as
the best study notes there and we also
did citations to basically kind of
create this trust in the in the
the olation is currently still running
so we're currently looking at data so
far looks again lar because again it's
latency issue latency topic still isn't
solved um and we also still see the
trend that students just want to have
content in the end um but we keep you
posted how it's
going cool um so let's quickly summarize
what we over learned so far um on the LM
side so first thing is that I mentioned
earlier uh LMS enable us to build MVPs a
lot faster so especially in a smaller
team such as we are previously building
features such as Google SL questions
would have taken multiple weeks human
labor and so on which we don't have so
it just enables us to do things a lot
faster and on our
scale secondly uh llms work well for
index time things but not for search
time tasks so basically everything can
happen once and run on your documents um
that's pretty good at there's I'm really
good at that because you can you have
enough time for that but running stuff
on search time tasks so while user
search
that gets pretty tricky because in the
end latency is always an issue and there
just also more cost because you have
more searches and they you have also new
searches every day so we also the things
that actually worked and the things we
use in production are main actually
mainly index time
us other thing is that llms actually
make the classical ml task a lot faster
the previously branding classification
model would have been a huge undertaking
again requiring human labeling again
having biases by those humans which
needs review and so on and nowadays we
just put it into db4 vision and just run
it through and it makes it a lot lot
faster which also helps us to build more
of those classification
models and uh lastly is basically that
the current LMS you can't get the three
best things you can't get high quality
speed and being cheap yet so I think as
you also see models get better and
better over time so I guess at some
point the models will be actually cheap
fast and good but currently they're not
so that's all something to to plan
with then what we actually also saw is
that scale is always an issue in our
case so basically we have huge amount of
searches huge amount of documents which
makes it pretty tricky um and basically
that's always something to fact on mind
but I said again it will also get better
in the future other thing is that LMS
are not a magic wand so you can use them
and they're helpful for certain things
but in the end you still need to think
about user problem and you still need to
actually think about what does the
student want here in this case and then
LMS can be a tool to build a solution
but you still need to actually figure
out what's the right solution to build
um and as you've seen with the AI and
search tickets also the solutions we
have sometimes just don't work and also
students don't like it so again it's
really important to still think about or
do the research on what students
actually need in their lives and then
may be based on that build features and
I guess the last maybe most important
thing is that if we look back at the
last year or half a year the non llm
changes actually work the best so the
classical stuff of just tuning stuff of
doing doing more on the ranking based on
user interactions uh understanding more
what the actual grade level of user kind
of things actually had a better success
rate than all the LM stuff with probably
less effort um so even though LMS are
quite helpful um nevertheless the non LM
stuff also is quite quite
important cool that's it from our side
thanks a lot for listening
and fantastic and uh you came up with
that that presentation over the weekend
which I think very impressive I finished
it yesterday in the train in the train
yeah what they call what my colleague
Eric calls conference driven development
yes okay so uh do we have any questions
right I'll just come over here with the
first
one I'll try and get to you all we've
got some
time uh thanks very much I one comment I
feel like you don't trust llms very much
and a question um you mentioned a
meaningful event for a success for
search result is 120 seconds of DW do
you have anything else like students
adding it to later sharing with their
friends anything else like that yeah
yeah concretely actually it's it's
basically uh 120 seconds or saving or
doing a screenshot that's concretely the
definition yeah and but on your first
point we don't trust LMS and I think
actually that's also learning that you
shouldn't trust them because in the end
they always will produce bullshits on
point and actually to handle that check
that yeah great thank you so we have a
question from who is it from Sam online
uh who said thanks for your interesting
talk uh about building your know graph
can you give examples of duplication in
llm outputs what's the example of an
output that required
cleaning oh yeah sure like causes of War
reasons of
War so like of course like we clean up
everything which is like exact duplicate
so basically everything that is a
duplicate from a stamp version but then
you you go to the area of like
semantic uh duplicate
which which we don't
need okay thank you okay we had a wow
bit scared now uh T
think thank you for amazing talk I mean
this is really interesting and um I feel
like with such a small team size you've
done an amazing job you have oh outdone
yourself one of the things which
probably you might have covered I mean I
could behave like an llm lost in the
middle sort to say so I kind of feel
like uh the evaluation part I mean how
did you evaluate because you cannot
master all the subjects that you've
covered in your application so don't you
think you're like little shot on the
Manpower like in terms of U kind of the
experts of the uh each subject to verify
if your results are how student expects
expect them to be so basically mean on
the content side that we might lack or
have issues there yeah I think our
philosophy always was that we we kind of
solve that for scale because the end if
you look at Germany for example we have
have around 700,000 content pieces in
German so there might be the case that
one content piece is wrong or that stuff
is missing but in the end uh we can base
on user metric and based us engagement
actually understand what's the content
that helps students the most what
actually helps the most to learn for the
exam and based on that can actually
filter out the ones that are not correct
and basically that's focus on the ones
actually correct so the end something
that we since it this user generated we
actually have all the content we have 20
50 content pieces on one topic and
actually figure out what's the best
content for this topic
great thank you um so another question
from Jack online do you use an
off-the-shelf AB testing system for
search or have you built your own
internal framework we built our own uh
so we started around I mean when we
started we started with Firebase back
then uh but then pretty early on moved
to our own system because we run a test
company so it's kind of a quite integral
part so we basically buildt a the whole
assignment logic but we also buil our
own evaluation tool around that awwesome
it would be great to hear more about
that and open source it even um because
it is one of those gaps really we don't
have great open source AB testing stuff
I believe so uh let's take another
question for I know there are lots of
you I'll get to as many as as I can but
I'm going to come back
here you've also mentioned the the
triangle of can't be fast deep and good
but it might be in the future I think
this is a more general question to to
everyone won't our and user expectations
always be so that it The Cutting Edge
will be what we want to do for every
task but then it's still expensive
because good kind of the mark for good
just keeps going forward yeah guess it's
probably r thing for us as like tech
people but I would say the average 13y
old school kid doesn't probably even
know what an L is so they just care
about getting a good answer and I don't
think that their quality c will likely
improve a lot uh I think there is just
more what the models will catch up to
what currently already
exists okay thanks I I've got a
14-year-old kid all he cares about is
Minecraft frankly so um okay another
question online uh let's go to
uh uh okay I think some of these been
answered but I come to this one the
contents from it's user generated
content but goes through review um how
do you deal with limiting misinformation
yeah I mean we we in the beginning
actually started with human reviewing
all of content uh but soon notice it
doesn't doesn't scale uh so at some
point also switch to ml models on that
but on the misinformation side I guess
what actually was all surprising for us
is that students are quite eager to
report stuff so in the end you can if
you just give them a report button they
would rather over report and under
report so we just actually filter a lot
of stuff by just having a report button
on there and then basically then going
through the content that gets reported
and actually filters out about
everything thank you I'm very sorry
we're going to have to leave it there uh
if you do have questions for Gregor or
Alexandra I believe they'll be around
for a little while and I'm sure they'll
be happy to answer things here or by a
slack or something but please thank you
very much for stepping into the breach
and Applause fantastic
talk thank you